Kaspars Upenieks

Date of birth: 16/11/1993 Nationality: Latvian (+44) 7856678878

kasparsupenieks@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/public-profile/in/kaspars-upenieks-34a6b4102/

Whatsapp Messenger: +447856678878

13 Cleveland Drive, OX4 3HA, Oxford, United Kingdom

About me: I am a highly competent data warehouse software developer with 6-year experience developing a wide range of data warehouse/ETL/SQL solutions. I understand data warehouse project lifecycle in-depth and am very capable at all aspects of development from project planning to requirements gathering through writing and testing code, creating documentation and support. I am currently seeking long-term positions which will allow me to further improve my skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/12/2014 - 01/03/2015 - Riga, Latvia

INTERNSHIP AS ANDROID DEVELOPER - EMERGN

Working in a team of 3-5 programmers on Android mobile software application development, which included working with Android legacy codebase and version control to achieve higher team productivity. As well as developing new Android widgets that were capable of communicating with the current software application. The achieved result was Android base software application that was used in the company's conference rooms, completely capable of displaying work schedules, temperature, current time and other customizable widgets. Furthermore, Agile methodology documentation of the project was made, to describe project functions and requirement implementation.

02/03/2015 – CURRENT – Riga, Latvia

PROGRAMMER/ETL DEVELOPER – EMERGN

Working with Latvian State revenue department data warehouse Agile/Kanban team. Main responsibility is implementing ETL solutions in an existing data warehouse using SAP BODS, IBM DataStage and Pentaho ETL tools. As a result, additional skills like ODBC, JDBC connections and SQL in different database systems(MS SQL, Informix, Sybase, Oracle, Netezza) were adapted.

Other projects include:

- SAP HANA,
- Jira/Git version control,
- · Web development (HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript),
- Java SE(clients),
- System analytics,
- · Code supervision,
- Web Services(SOAP, REST)
- Scripting languages.

Work outcome: Client is provided with functioning schedulable ETL processes and other software for data warehouse with full software development cycle support to make better business decisions.

Information and communication

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2017 - 27/06/2019 - Riga, Latvia

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE - University of Latvia

Formal grammatic; Databases; Computer graphics and image processing; Mathematical logic; Linux system programming; IT project management; CKAN framework and structured data usage in web.

First

C++ programming; Web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, NodeJS); Computer-system administration (LAMP, WAMP); Mathematics (Discrete mathematics, Mathematical analytics, Analytic geometry); Databases (MS Sql); Computer-system architecture; Software Engineering.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): LATVIAN

Other language(s):

	011521101711151110		01 27 ii (ii 10		***************************************
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C1	C1	C2
RUSSIAN	C1	C2	B2	B2	B2

SPEAKING

WRITING

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

UNDERSTANDING

PROJECTS

Open data project for Latvian state revenue department

This project consistent of three main parts:

- -Report export from SAP Restful framework using Java client; -
- ETL development using SAP BODS;
- -Data Upload with Java client for CKAN framework.

In result i created data transformation job which can be scheduled and extracts data from SAP Bussines Object reports and uploads data on Latvian government open data portal data.gov.lv

Other projects

Other project include using different technology for alternate solutions, like creating different clients in Java SE, Python. Doing some web development tasks or machine learning basic tasks.

Data transformation\ETL jobs

Main area of my daily work. Creating different data transformation jobs using SAP BODS(biggest expertise), Pentaho, IBM Datastage products and different databases like Netezza, Sybase IQ, SAP HANA, Oracle, IBM Informix, MS SQL. All of those products were mainly designed for Latvian State revenue department data warehouse purposes.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Interests

After computer science field I could say that my other passion is finance/economic. In high school years participated in many Latvian and Baltic economic competitions and currently actively invest in stock market.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication\organisational skills

Good communication and organisational skills gained through my experience working in IT field with different teams of 2-10 people. Also working in Kanban methodology team with daily stand-ups and different version control\work reporting systems.

OTHER

Jobe related courses\skills

- e-Guardion and ECDL Computer skills sertificate BDA
- JAVA SE 8 Fundamentals Diploma from Oracle University
- Java SE 8 Fundamentals Ed 1 Sertificate
 Code Institutes 5 day coding challenge certificate